Mss.Printed .Material
American Philosophical Society
Printed Material
n. d.
Mss.Printed .Material
American Philosophical Society
100.0 Volume(s)
Artificial Collection, created to facilitate new naming scheme via AT. Material saved to this collection will be linked from CONTENTdm to the OPAC.
- Frontispiece, Biographical anecdotes of the founders of the French Republic., 1797
- Various figures from Experiement on Electricity.
- William Henley's Experiments concerning the different efficacy of pointed and blunted rods, Title Page.
- Articles of Confederation & Perpetual Union Between the States of New-Hampshire, Massachusetts-bay, Rhode-Island, Connecticut, New-York, New-Jersey, Pennsylvania, the counties of New-Castle, Kent & Sussex on Delaware, Maryland, Virginia, North-Carolina.
- A Map of North Carolina.
- Title page from first edition Thomas Paine's Common Sense.
- Title page of first edition of The American Crisis.
- "...Circles of the sphere projected on the Meridian Stereographically."
- De System Ptolomai.
- De System Copernicia.
- De System Tychonis Brahei.
- Philosophical Differation of the Sphere, and the Motion of the Celestial Bodies.
- The Mundan Theory of Ptolomy, or the Old System.
- The Theory of Copernicus.
- Diagram showing sperical movement of the planets.
- Magic Cyclovolute
- Eclipsis Solaris.
- View of the Triumphal Arch, and the manner of receiving General Washington at Trenton, on his route to New York.
- Maps
  - A chart of the zodiacal stars, used in finding the longitude at sea by the moon. And their hourly positions to the circumpolar stars, both above and below the north and south poles.
  - [Map of the moon accompanied by an explanation of the figures and letters]., ca. 1832
  - General-Karte der sichtbaren Seite der Mondoberflaeche zugleich als übersichts-Blatt zur grössern Mondkarte von Wilh. Beer und Joh. Heinr. Mädler.
  - Carte des parties principales du globe terrestre pour servir à l'histoire des deux premiers siècles depuis la création du monde
  - Chart of the world, according to Mercator's projection, shewing the latest discoveries of Capt. Cook.
  - To George Washington president of the United States of America this magnetic atlas or variation chart is humbly inscribed by John Churchman.
  - A correct chart of the terraqueous globe, on which are described lines shewing the variation of the magnetic needle in the most frequented seas; originally composed in the year 1700 by the celebrated Dr. Edmund Halley; renewed by William Mountaine and James Dodson, F R S according to observations made about the year 1756.
  - A new and authentic map of the world embracing all the recent discoveries, and exhibiting particularly the nautical researches of the most distinguished circumnavigators from the latest & best authorities with numerous corrections & additions, by H. S. Tanner, 1831.
  - Chart exhibiting the discoveries of the Second American Grinnell Expedition in search of Sir John Franklin.
  - Chart showing the discoveries tracks and surveys of the Arctic Exploring Expedition of 1860 and 1861. I. I. Hayes, M.D., commanding. Newly projected from revised materials discussed for the Smithsonian Institution by Charles A. Schott.
  - The Arctic regions comprising the most recent explorations of Robert E. Peary, Fridtjov Nansen, and F. Jackson, by Prof. Angelo Heilprin.
  - Carte générale du théâtre de la guerre.
  - Geological map of Europe executed under the direction of Joseph Prestwich, F.R.S. by William Topley, F.G.S., and J.G. Goodchild, F.G.S. from the latest surveys.
  - London docks. Plan of the River Thames with the proposed docks and cut.
  - A new map of Ireland divided into its provinces, counties and baronies, wherein are distinguished the bishopricks, borroughs, barracks, bogs, passes, bridges &c. with the principal roads, and the common reputed miles. According to the newest and most exact observations.
  - The VII United Provinces. Corrected from the observations communicated to the Royal Society at London, and ye Royal Academy at Paris.Humbly dedicated to Elihu Yale Esq. 1709.
  - Betuwe. 19. Ministerie van Oorlog. Topographisch Bureau.
  - La Turgovie avec le Lac de Constance, et des Pays Circonvoisins. Nova landgraviatus Turgoviae chorographica tabula, ubi Scaphusiensis, Abbatisque Cellanae respublicae specialiter designatae proponuntur: nec non abbatia Sancti Galli, Episcopatus Constantinus, Toggenburgensisque comitatus, cum omnibus insertis, et contiguis comitatibus Dominüs, et Confinibus; omnia ex probatissimis subsidüs accuratissime et juxta limites delineata per Ioh. Ant. Rizzi Zannoni.
  - Die Eisgebyrge des Schweizerlandes, mit allen dabey vorkommenden Mineralien. In ihrem zusammenhang vorgestelt von G. S. Gruner.
  - Geologische Karte der Umgebung von Brugg (Aargau) von C. Moesch.
  - Le pais de Brie.
  - Tableau général des postes, l'année 1779.
  - Plan historique de la ville de Lyon et de ses quartiers, assujetti à ses accroissements embellissments, et projets.
  - Vues & coupes du Cap de la Hève. Profit du Cap.
  - Monographic géologique des anciens glaciers et du terrain érratique de la partie moyenne du bassin du Rhône par A. Falsan & E. Chantre.
  - [Lon]gitudinal section of the first 38 2/3 English miles of the railway for joining the [Mol]dau and the Danube... with the Elbe, and the Black Sea with the northern ocean, by means of the continent, executed under the superintendence of [the Ch]evalier Francis Anthony Gerstner. The [ac]t of the Emperor of Austria was... 1824, the work begun 28, July 1825 and the 38 2/3 english miles were completely finished at the end of the year 1828.
  - Basis novae chartae Palatinae... By Christian Mayer.
  - Plan of the River Viguo, and Port de Rande. Situated in the north part of Spain, in the kingdom of Gallice... by Joseph Smith Speer.
  - Ilha de Leão com asilhetas e fortes adjacentes ciudade e porto de Cadix com seus baixos &c. D. Vicente Tofino.
  - Pianta topografica della città di Napoli in Campagna Felice.
  - Pianta della città di Firenze nelle sue vere misure; colla descrizione dei luoghi più notabili di ciascun quartiere.
  - Carte de l'isle d'Elbe, dressée d'après les opérations trigonométriques extraites du traité de géodésie de Mr. Puissant.
  - Plan of Jerusalem by F. Catherwood, Architect, July, 1835.
  - Korea or Cho-sen of the Japanese.
  - [Chinese maps of Canton and Hong Kong, China. Ca. 1820].
  - A map of North America with the European settlements & whatever else is remarkable in ye West Indies, from the latest and best observations.
  - A map of the British Empire in North America; by Samuel Dunn.
  - North America and the West Indies, with the opposite coasts of Europe and Africa.
  - The Eskimo tribes of north-east America. By Franz Boas.
  - The United States of America with the British possessions of Canada, Nova Scotia, & of Newfoundland, divided with the French; and the Spanish territories of Louisiana and Florida according to the preliminary articles of peace signed at Versailles the 20th of Jan[uar]y 1783.
  - Sketch of the solar system for the use of schools.
  - Carte des États-Unis de l'Amérique suivant le traité de paix de 1783. Dédiée et présentée à, S. Excellence Mr. Benjamin Franklin ministre plenipotentiare des États-Unis de l'Amérique près la Cour de France, anc. présid. de la conventiõ de Pensilvanie et de la société philosophique de Philadelphia, &c. &c. Par son très humble et très obeissant serviteur Lattré. 1784
  - A map of the United States, exhibiting the post-roads, the situations, connections & distances of the post-offices stage roads, counties, ports of entry and delivery for foreign vessels, and the principal rivers.
  - A map historical and biographical chart.
  - Map of the United States of America.
  - United States of America.
  - Weather map.
  - Map showing the rail road and canal lines used in the determination of elevations by James T. Gardner, geographer.
  - Profile with the spirit level, of the due north line from the monument at the source of the River St. Croix to the St. John, surveyed in 1840 & 1841 under the direction of Major J. D. Graham... one of the commissioners for surveying and exploring the N. E. boundary of the U.S. U.S. Topographical Engineers.
  - Chart of the harbors of Salem, Marblehead, Beverly and Manchester.
  - Survey across the Isthmus of Cape Cod state of Massachusetts and town of Sandwich of a proposed canal between Buzzard's and Barnstable bays. 1825.
  - Salem harbor, Massachusetts.
  - Plan of Boston in New England with its environs, including Milton, Dorchester, Roxbury, Brookline, Cambridge, Medford, Charlestown, parts of Malden and Chelsea.
  - A map of Pensilvania, New-Jersey, New-York, and the three Delaware counties: by Lewis Evans.
  - A map of the middle British colonies in North America.
  - A map of the country between Albermarle Sound and Lake Erie, comprehending the whole of Virginia, Maryland, Delaware and Pennsylvania, with parts of several other of the United States of America.
  - A chart of Delaware Bay and River, containing a full and exact description of the shores, creeks, harbours, soundings, shoals, sands and bearings of the most considerable land marks, &c. &c.
  - Plan of the city of New York.
  - A map exhibiting a general view of the roads and inland navigation of Pennsylvania, and part of the adjacent states.
  - Battle field of Gettysburg.
  - Delaware River from Cherry Island flats to Bridesburg.
  - Philadelphie, par Eas[t]burn.
  - Plan of the city of Philadelphia and environs.
  - This new map of the city of Philadelphia for the use of fire men and others is most respectfully dedicated to the citizens and members of the engine & hose companies, by... John A. Paxton.
  - Map of Philadelphia County, constructed by virtue of an act of the legislature of Pennsylvania.
  - Map of Washington Square, Walnut Street, Philadelphia.
  - Map of the city of Philadelphia, together with all the surrounding districts, including Camden, N. J., from official records, plans of the district surveyor & original surveys by J. C. Sydney. 1849.
  - The Philadelphia Parkway as planned for the Fairmount Park Association.
  - A map of the head of Chesapeake Bay and Susquehanna River.
  - Plan of the city of Washington in the territory of Columbia, ceded by the states of Virginia and Maryland to the United States of America, and by them established as the seat of their government, after the year MDCCC.
  - The seat of war of the revolution in the southern states; shewing the principal movements of the hostile armies.
  - Chart of the lights on the lake coast of the United States.
  - A plan of the several villages in the Illinois country, with part of the River Mississippi &c.
  - Map of the Mississippi River from its source to the mouth of the Missouri: laid down from the notes of Lieut. Z. M. Pike, by Anthony Nav. Reduced, and corrected by the astronomical observations of Mr. Thompson at its source: and of Capt. M. Lewis, where it receives the waters of the Missouri.
  - Carte de la Louisiane et du cours du Mississippi dressée sur un grand nombre de mémoires, entrau tres [sic] sur ceux de M. de le Maire, par Guillaume de l'lsle de l'Académie R[oya]le des Sciences.
  - Ground plan [of the] Louisiana Purchase Exposition, St. Louis, Missouri. Worlds Fair. 1904.
  - The Strait of Magalhaens, commonly called Magellan.
  - Chiloe and parts of the adjacent coasts from H.M.S. Beagle.
  - Maury's wind and current chart.
  - Carte de la Polynesie ou la cinquième partie de la terre [title also in Swedish].
  - Remarques sur la navigation de Terre-Neuve à New-York afin d'éviter les Courrants et les bas-fonds au sud de Nantuckett et du Banc de George.
  - Indischer Ocean.
  - Atlas of New Jersey.
  - District of Pennsylvania...
  - Portraiture of the city of Philadelphia in the province of Pennsylvania in America.
  - Map of Philadelphia and parts adjacent.
  - Plan of the city of Philadelphia, compiled from actual surveys by F. Drayton, 1824.
  - Map of eastern Kentucky, shewing the western outcrop of its coal field as determined by the surveys of 1858 and 1859.
  - [Chart of the North Atlantic Ocean. 1792].
  - A new map of part of North America from the latitude of 40 to 68 degrees.
  - A New Chart of the Parts where a North West Passage was Sought in the Years 1746 and 1747.
  - ... .Map of the city and liberties of Philadelphia, with the catalogue of purchasers, is humbly dedicated by their most obedient humble servant, John Reed.
  - To the Honorable Thomas Penn and Richard Penn... and to John Penn... map of the province of Pennsylvania.
  - Nuova pianta dell'inclita città di Venezia recolata l'anno 1787.